Kiran Gowda N

kirangowdan1245@gmail.com | +917019038656| github/kiru134| LinkedIn/kiran-gowda-n

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

• Python • Javascript • Golang

FRAMEWORKS

- React.js Python-FastAPI
- gRPC REST Cypress

BIG DATA

- Databricks PySpark Hadoop
- •Cassandra Hive Kafka

TOOLS

- Airflow Kubernetes (GKE)
- Docker Git Jenkins Jira

DATABASES

• MySQL• PostgreSQL• Mongo DB

LINKS

LeetCode://Kiran-Gowda-N/ Github://kiru134 LinkedIn://kiran-gowda-n

EDUCATION

AMBEDKAR INSTITUTE OF

TECHNOLOGY

Eng-Electronics and Communication Grade: 9.2/10

Aug-2017 - July 2021

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received **Outstanding Performance** Award for contribution in Realogy Project.
- Got A Team Award and peer Appreciation.
- Exhibited **Humanoid Robot** in Karnataka State Council for Science and Technology.

PUBLICATIONS

[1] KiranGowdaN. Front desk humanoid officer using cnn algorithm. International Journal for Research in Applied Science Engineering Technology, PaperID= IJRASET37247, 2021.

CERTIFICATION

BigData TrendyTech Online Program

PROFILE SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in Full Stack development. Skilled in developing interactive Websites using React.js framework, developing microservices using Python FastAPI, Go, deploying the applications in Google Kubernetes Engine and also have experience with various Big Data technologies such as PySpark, Kafka, Spark-Streaming, AWS Databricks, configuring workflows using Airflow and deploying data solutions using AWS(EMR,Redshift,S3,Athena).

EXPERIENCE

LTIMINDTREE | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROJECT- 2 Cloud as a Service - Jan 2023 - Present | Bangalore, KA

- Contributed towards **Multi-Region Deployment and Disaster Control** feature along with regulating background jobs.
- Developed bridge APIs to connect multiple microservices.
- Increased the throughput of the services by more than **50%** and reduced API response time by **60%**.
- Configured **Kafka** Producers and consumer groups to serve the events to relevant microservices.
- Enhanced user experience and accomplished webpage objectives by creating **site structure**, **navigation** using **React JS**.
- Stack: Python-FastAPI, MVC Design, Redis, Docker, React. js, HTML5, CSS3

PROJECT-1 Realogy [ERA] -Oct 2021 -Nov 2022 | Bangalore, KA

- Worked as a **React developer** for real-estate client, Realogy.
- Involved in creating new features, functionality and capabilities on the real-estate website using HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, **React JS**.
- Integrating with **CMS** and involved in resolving various operational issues that affect order flow to/from the interfacing systems.
- Implemented **stable React functional components** and **stand-alone** functions to be added to any future pages.
- Worked on an **Agile Development** Team to deliver regular updates to business team and project managers.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

INSTASOCIAL | REACT JS, REDUX, REACT-MUI, PYTHON-FASTAPI, SQLALCHEMY.POSTGRESQL

- A **Social Media Platform** provides Photo sharing service as **Posts**, users can follow each other, **comment** on Posts and communicate with each other in real-time using **messaging** service, Implemented Authentication using **oAuth2** with Password, hashing, Bearer with **JWT Tokens**.
- Built Front-End with React js, used Redux architecture for global state management. Developed Backend middleware using Python FastAPI and PostgreSQL database.

Web App-HOSTED HERE|GITHUB FastAPI-HOSTED HERE|GITHUB

GO-MICRONET |GOLANG, GRPC, RABBITMQ, DOCKER-SWARM, MONGODB

- Built a scalable resilient distributed microservices application in Golang
- Streamed messages between the microservices using gRPC and RPC protocols and leveraged AMQP-RabbitMQ for forwarding the client request to other microservices. GITHUB